HOST: If speaking up at work makes you anxious, this episode is for you.
COACH: Most professionals are not afraid of hard work. They are afraid of social rejection.
HOST: So they stay quiet, stay agreeable, and slowly lose their voice.
COACH: And the cost is high. You get temporary approval but long-term invisibility.
HOST: How do we change that without becoming aggressive?
COACH: Use the clarity triangle: values, language, and emotional steadiness.
HOST: Step one: define your non-negotiables before the meeting starts.
COACH: If you don't define your line in advance, pressure will define it for you.
HOST: Step two: use respectful assertive language.
COACH: Try this phrase: I see your point, and my recommendation is this.
HOST: Step three: expect disagreement and stay regulated.
COACH: Disagreement is not danger. It's information.
HOST: Your 7-day challenge: one clear boundary, one honest contribution, one calm follow-up.
COACH: Track one metric: did you communicate with integrity, yes or no.
HOST: You don't need everyone to agree with you.
COACH: You need to become someone you can trust in the room.